a group of 50,000 selfemployed women in
India have become the first
beneficiaries of an in Innovative
insurance program that provides
financial assistance when temperatures
reach dangerous extremes routs reported
yesterday as temperatures climbed above
40° which is 104 fahit from May 18th to
the 25th the women in Rajasthan Gujarat
and Mahar Maharashtra received a flat $5
payment additionally 92% of the women
received further payouts tied to the
local conditions and duration of the
heat with some earning up to
$19.8 each designed by nonprofit climate
resilience for all and India's
self-employed women's Association this
program combines Insurance payouts and
direct cash assistance to support
vulnerable communities impacted by
extreme weather the total payments
across the initiative amounted to 300
4,553 underwritten by reinsurer Swiss re
and provided locally by ICICI Lombard
this novel approach highlights the
growing use of insurance as a tool to
rapidly deliver financial aid to those
affected by climate related disasters